I would like to ask the head teacher to explain to me:
em xin cô chủ nhiệm chỉ dạy cho em biết
In our group practice session, there are
được là trong buổi tu tập C nhóm em có
10 of us. If we dedicate the merit of
10 người chúng em hồi hướng cho buổi tu
that day's practice to one person, is the
tập ngày hôm đó cho một người thì công
merit and power different from dedicating it to 10
đức và năng lực có khác hồi hướng cho 10
people? I am grateful for
người không ạ em xin tri ân công đức chỉ
your guidance. Oh, it's not different, dear fellow practitioners.
dạy của cô ạ Ơ không khác đâu có quý đạo
That merit is the
hữu ạ nhé vì cái công đức đấy là cái tâm
intention of our hearts. When we
mong muốn của chúng ta chúng ta Hồi
dedicate it within the Six Harmonies, it's no different from dedicating it
Hướng trong cái Lục Hòa nó không khác
to one person who
chúng ta hồi hướng cho một người người
relies on us.
ta lương tượng vào mình ấ mà các quý đạu
Do you understand this point, dear fellow practitioners? If someone relies on
Hữu rõ chỗ này chưa ạ người ta nương tựa
you, if they rely on the Dharma of
vào mình người ta nương tựa vào Pháp Hòa
Harmony, then anyone who relies on you will receive the merit.
hợp thì ai nương tựa mình hồi hướng đều
For example, with the
mình đều hồi hướng được hết Ví dụ như
Buddha, if one person makes an offering
đức phật ấy một người cúng
with such a heart, and the Buddha dedicates it,
dường với tâm như vậy đức phật hồi hướng
that person still receives the same merit.
cái người đó vẫn hưởng phước như thế
But if 10 people with the same heart make an offering
nhưng 10 người có tâm như vậy cúng dường
to the Buddha, and the Buddha dedicates it, they still receive the same merit.
cho phật phật hồi hướng vẫn Phước như
No one ever loses their merit. The
thế mà không bao giờ có ai bị mất Phước
important thing is that the person
đi hết quan trọng là cái người người mà
you wish to dedicate it to is the one
người ta mong hồi hướng ấy là tâm người
whose heart relies on the Dharma.  How does the club work?
ta nương tựa vào câu lạc bộ như thế nào
Ten people rely on it, and ten
thôi 10 người cùng nương tựa thì 10
people share the same merit.
người hồi hướng Phước báo đều như nhau
This is the merit of the Dharma, dear fellow practitioners,
đây là công đức của Pháp có quý đạo hữu
not the merit of any
nhé chứ không phải là công đức của của
one person. Because we
một cái người nào đó là do chúng ta
rely on the Dharma and practice it, the
nương tựa vào pháp mà chúng ta thực hành
person who practices it also receives merit. Dear fellow practitioners, do you
cái người thực hành đó cũng được Phước
understand this? And
có Quý độu Hữu rõ chỗ này chưa ạ và cái
whoever relies on the Dharma receives
người nào nương tựa và pháp cũng được
merit; we just mention their name. So we
Phước có cái là chúng ta đọc tên ra thôi
are all people
nhá nên chúng ta cũng cũng là người đang
relying on the Dharma, therefore we can
nương tựa vào pháp mà cho nên chúng ta
freely dedicate merit to those who
hồi hướng thoải mái nếu với những ai
rely on us, like you, dear fellow practitioners.
nương tựa vào chúng ta như các quý đạo
There's no fear of that merit diminishing,
hữu nhá Không sợ cái Phước đó giảm đi
except when you, dear fellow practitioners, make offerings and
đâu chỉ trừ bao giờ các quý đạo hữu cúng
dedicate merit to a deceased person. If
dường hồi hướng cho vong linh nào đó th
you understand this, then the
quý đạo hữu rõ chỗ này chưa ạ thì cái
merit of the offering is divided; if there are three deceased persons, then it's divided;
Phước báo cúng dường đấy nó có chia ra
if there are three deceased persons, then it's divided; if there are three deceased persons,
nếu ba vong linh thì ba vong linh phải
then it's
chia ra một vong linh thì một vong linh
divided; but the merit of practicing,
chia ra còn cái công đức tu tập tụng
chanting, bowing, and spreading the Dharma is
kinh Bái xám thực Hoành pháp thì nó lại
not divided like the merit of giving.
không không bị chia như là cái Công Đức
Dear fellow practitioners, do you understand this? Mindful contemplation, contemplation,
Tài thí quý đạ hữ rõ chỗ này chưa ạ tâm
etc.  Let me give you an example to help you
chiếu Hoàn quán ví dụ cho quý Đạ Hữu
understand, my esteemed friends. For instance, if you give
hiểu thế này ạ Ví dụ nếu như mà tâm
10,000 instances of the Perfect Contemplation
chiếu Hoàn quán có 10.000 tâm chiếu Hoàn
to one person, that person receives
quán cho một người thì một người đó được
more. This is about material gain; one
nhiều hơn Đây nói về Tịnh tài nhá một
person receives more, but if you give it to
người thì một người nhiều hơn nhưng cho
five people, each of them receives
năm người thì năm người mỗi người được
less. However, the giving of fearlessness, which is the
ít hơn Thế còn cái bố thí vô úy tức là
saying that brings
câu nói khiến cho người ta giác ngộ
enlightenment and peace, is not
người ta được an vui thì nó lại không bị
divided like that. If you give one instance of the Perfect Contemplation and say
chia ra như thế tâm chếu hoàn quán nói
one sentence,
một câu nếu một ngườ người được hoan hỉ
and one person is happy, then they are also enlightened. If
thì cái họ cũng được giác ngộ như thế mà
ten people are happy, then
10 người người ta được hoan hỉ thì người
they are also enlightened. So,
ta cũng được giác ngộ như thế cho nên là
these two types of giving are different. One is
hai cái việc bố thí này nó khác nhau một
giving material gain. Do you
cái bố thí bằng Tịnh tài các quý đạu Hữu
understand this point, my esteemed friends? The division has some meaning,
rõ chỗ này chưa thì chia ra nó có ý tí
but giving merit through enlightenment is the same. Do you
nhưng bố thí bằng công đức giác ngộ thì
understand this point, my esteemed friends? The
nó như nhau các quý Đạ Hữu rõ chỗ này
important thing is
chưa ạ Quan trọng là cái người người ta
how a person relies on the Dharma. The Dharma determines what they receive.
lương tựa vào cái Pháp như thế nào đâu
Therefore, the merit of the Dharma is
như thế cho nên công đức của Pháp là bất
inconceivable, my esteemed friends.  Dear
khả tư nghỉ các quý đạo hữu ạ nhé các
Dharma friends, if you practice the Six Harmonies, then whoever
quý đạo hữu cứ thực hành nục hòa thì ai
relies on this Dharma and we
nương tựa vào pháp này chúng ta hồi
dedicate the merit to them will receive a
hướng Phước báo của họ đều được rất
great deal, and our merit will not be
nhiều và phước báo của chúng ta không
lost but only increased. Do you understand? So
mất mà chỉ có tăng lên thôi quý đạo hiểu
rest assured, only with money will
ạ nhá Cho nên yên tâm chỉ có bằng tiền
it decrease because it is a material offering.
thì nó mới giảm đi vì nó là có cái vật
And when we give alms with
thí Thế còn khi chúng ta bố thí bằng vật
material things, we generate
thí thì chúng ta lại sinh ra một loại
another kind of merit. Do you understand? When
công đức nữa các quý đo hu rõ chưa ạ khi
we give alms with pure money, offering it to the
chúng ta bố thí bằng Tịnh tài cúng dường
Three Jewels and dedicating it to the departed souls,
tam bảo hồi hướng cho các cái vong linh
we add another merit: the
thì trong đó chúng ta lại thêm cái một
merit of saving the
cái công đức là công đức đi mà cứu độ
departed souls. That's
vong ninh Đấy thêm một cái công đức đó
another merit, as you understand, dear Dharma friends. So when
nữa như các quý đầu Hữu nhé cho nên
we chant scriptures and dedicate the merit, it belongs to the
chúng ta tụng kinh hồi hướng đó thuộc về
Dharma giving, dear Dharma friends. The enlightenment of
Pháp thí các quý đạo hữu ạ nhá sự giác
Dharma giving, so when we dedicate it
ngộ pháp thí cho nên chúng ta hồi hướng
to the many, they will all receive it. If
cho số đông đều được Nếu như những người
those people rely on our Six Harmonies, they will all
đó nương tựa vào pháp Lục Hòa của chúng
enjoy the merit.
ta thì người đó đều được hưởng cái Phước
[Music]
[âm nhạc]
[Applause]
[Vỗ tay]